did we learn nothing from the whole
Tanner Pete yorski situation like we
talked about that on the on the Pod
before right Tanner dropped a uh Cash
Money dropped a mega crit on Pete on
like Christmas day one time and Pete had
to like leave his family on Christmas
day to go deal with this like really bad
bug
[Music]
[Applause]
hey everyone this is techno geek here
just wanted to give a quick shout out to
our latest sponsor project Discovery now
project Discovery makes a lot of tools
that you probably know of or have even
used uh one of them is nuclei and the
latest release of nuclei is version 3.2
now 3.2 comes with a lot of really
awesome new features um two that I
really wanted to highlight here for you
are the authenticated scanning and the
advanced fuzzing support now for
authenticated scanning it used to be
that you would have to do all your
nuclei scanning against unauthenticated
end points or you'd have to add your
cookies manually all that kind of messy
no more it's all automatic you can use
existing login templates to
automatically log in to your application
and then you can run all your existing
nuclei templates against an
authenticated part of the application
now to really increase your coverage uh
the other that I mentioned is Advanced
fuzzing support now nuclea had added way
back in version 2.8 the ability to fuzz
different things but now they've
expanded this comprehensively across the
board so not only can you fuzz in the
normal spots but you can fuzz within
headers you can fuzz within cookies you
can fuzz within specific parts of the
body whether that's in Json or XML or
form data and so many more things so if
you want to learn more about what came
in nuclei 3.2 go ahead and check out the
the release blog post over at nu. g/p
podcast that's
nx. podcast
thanks all right Mr Mar what is that
face reflection my glasses
I keep it either up here or down here
somehow somehow you still have energy
after 14 hour flight so Props to you on
that where you at and what why are you
out there right now Joel yeah man yeah
I'm in the Jo anbg South Africa uh for a
meta bug Ry research conference so nice
they're doing a little bit of a a
conference SL live hacking event type of
thing out here they do one I think every
year um last year was in Soul South
Korea um and this year it's in
Johannesburg South Africa so that's
pretty pretty exciting I've uh I've
never been anywhere in Africa before uh
not alone South Africa so I'm super
super excited and awesome opportunity to
get to come is it Johannesburg or is it
Johannesburg oh geez I don't know uh uh
I'm gonna say Johannesburg because that
is I'm
[Laughter]
white all right gotcha well we'll leave
it at that for that I'm sure we're gonna
get roasted in the comments for that but
um Joel I've got I've got something for
you man while you were on this
flight uh flight to to something
hanburg uh the POC drop for the pdf.js
xss um the what the the pdf.js xss you
saw you oh man we we talked about that I
think for 5 seconds and then
uh this is what happens they start
dropping zero days on me well you know
this is what happens when you get a uh
when you get a business class flight
when you get upgraded to business class
and then you fall asleep so poor poor
Joel poor Joel and his full full Rec
reclining seat um full life FL life is
very difficult yeah yeah I believe
it um yeah so this one this one's was an
interesting man uh an interesting one
man and I I know the Wi-Fi was kind of
[__] on the plane and I know you
probably didn't get a bunch of time to
prep this time so I'll take this one and
and uh we'll keep this a little bit more
Q&A for this for this episode but um
yeah I wanted to I wanted to talk about
this one anyway this was on the list
even without the PC because I was like
ah wow you know the advisory actually
has some good information in it it's
like
essentially the xss occurs in the font
processing JavaScript code uh that that
the pdf.js generates and then it
proceeds to eval so uh it's been on my
to-do list to go and like find the P for
this uh because it should be pretty easy
to look through the code and figure out
where they're eving and then just kind
of work back from there and uh but they
beat me to it today Codi and labs
dropped um the PC for CV 2024
4367 um the xss and pdf.js and what I
didn't realize dude is this actually
affects every single uh Firefox
user because it uses it by
default yeah it's really crazy I mean so
we've talked about this a little bit
before right but um browser market share
for Firefox is less than 3% so yeah yeah
lot of there are a decent amount of
Firefox users uh but I think as hackers
were probably a little more biased
towards thinking that a lot more people
use Firefox than they do
that being said that's pretty bad yeah
it's pretty bad it's pretty bad and I
think there's a lot of there's a lot of
application as well in just other areas
uh you know applications using pdf.js to
display PDF so it was definitely one
that I was kind of looking into and
being like okay this is actually one to
keep in the in the in your mind you know
because it's one of those like
JavaScript libraries where uh or vules
in a JavaScript library where it's like
if the library is actually doing the
thing that it's supposed to do then it
should be vulnerable um and so whenever
like it might even be worthwhile to put
up some sort of alerting in in kaido or
in burp I know that burp does like the
vulnerable JS libraries either in
extension or or by default um this could
definitely be a good one to to keep an
eye out for um and and with regards to
the technical details for this one it
was super simple dude um essentially
what was happening is uh the code that
was being they were doing glyph
rendering um via JavaScript uh in in
inside of this pdf.js and essentially
what it would do is would take a part of
the PDF file um and it would integrate
it just just like place it directly into
a JavaScript code and then eval that
JavaScript code so in the end inter yeah
you could just you could specify a a
string in the specific section of the
font um and then that would actually
just get placed directly into the code
you just close off the function call and
run whatever code you want and that just
gets executed so really really clean PC
too and they actually dropped a uh proof
of concept PDF file so you don't even
have to generate the PDF file yourself
that's awesome that's awesome look at
that that's super interesting you know
what it makes me wonder is um if there's
a similar type of vulnerability in pdfm
uh which is the Chrome one right PDF is
that I think that's what it's called
pdfm okay yeah like chromium pdfm um
yeah I I do wonder I think it's a
totally separate thing but I would be
curious if there's been any Research
into it from that side cuz I'm very
surprised that something so um
fundamental as pdf.js would have uh been
exploitable and I'm looking at the uh
the payload here and this is super super
simple too yeah yeah it it'll be
interesting man you know I think it's
definitely worthwhile to take a look at
any sort of JS rendering of complex file
types I recently had a vulnerability
with my menty actually my mentee had a
vulnerability to give him full credit
like he really took it the full way um I
just kind of advised along the way um
but he had a vulnerability in a JS
library that was parsing a complex file
type and displaying it in the browser um
as a part of uh some some rendering and
you know it's just hard to do securely I
think there's lots of there's lots of
nuances to it so um that should
definitely be we we on this pod we like
to talk about attack vectors in areas
where you can you know attack stuff that
are probably going to be less discussed
by other uh by the traditional security
environment and I think this is one of
them if you're really willing to take
the Deep dive and audit a a library for
displaying specific types of files I
think there's often problems there yeah
so so did um did codian find this or was
was this a this was a vulnerability that
existed and they just got a PC for it no
they they found it um they didn't they
didn't like leak the PC or anything they
they um they found it themselves they
reported it to pdf.js and then or to
Milla and then they uh they disclosed
the PC so uh you know definitely respect
for COD and Labs here uh dropping the PC
for us which is nice you know it saves
us the time to go back and reverse it
I'm sure plenty of people reversed it
though um so yeah I think that's the
right call anyway to just to just expose
it and once the once the patches in
place absolutely I mean I think it's
also really fascinating when I'm looking
at the PC
like I can very clearly see how it
exploits but then when I read through
this whole write up it's significantly
more confusing coming from like the
white box approach where it's like how
does this code actually like exploit
this like what do you need to do to
match all this Criterion stuff versus if
you were just approaching this from a
black blackbox perspective I think it
actually would have been a lot easier oh
really wow that yeah I think so I mean
maybe if you just fuzz all the fields
right like versus trying to find some
sink and then going backwards you have
see the flow of the data you know um and
I think that is a little bit of a tricky
part um but it it does make me think of
another thing that was kind of on the
to-do list for day which is the nextjs
uh ssrf that um that Asin note released
which is just another great example of
sitting down and auditing some source
code resulting in a a really crazy set
of bugs did you get the chance to read
through this one before yeah I saw I saw
that they uh they had talked about this
a little bit I'm glad to see that it's
out now
uh I think I KN knew about this a little
bit ahead of time but okay got you got
the inside
scoop but this is really really cool um
yeah did we talk about this I feel like
we we might have mentioned this or
something right or or no we may have I I
don't know you know our apologies to to
the audience if it h if we have already
because we've had this on on the list
for a little while is also some of the
other items here um but we've been so
we've had the opportunity to interview
such great guests the past couple weeks
where it's like uh you know
there's just been a lot going on so but
I I just wanted to point out a couple
couple things here one just amazing uh
write up but I really liked how they one
that that there if you look at the code
flow um there seems to be a lot of
inhibiting factors right there's a head
a head request that's sent beforehand
and there's a specific content type that
has to come back and if you look at it
you know sort of at a glance you might
think oh okay well they've got
Protections in place that would make
this ssrf like not even possible um but
they don't they don't give up there they
continue to to to push through it and um
you know find a way to bypass the
content type limitation and use a
redirect to get past that so um I just
think it's a really a really high
quality piece of of research and just an
example of the stuff that the Asin note
team has been has been pushing
out yeah yeah I mean per usual Asin note
uh everything that they publish is going
to be super high quality and super
in-depth and super well uh researched so
I always love to see the stuff that
they're pushing out and the I just can't
I wish I could like subscribe somehow
you know yeah yeah I don't know I I feel
like maybe they have like a we might be
able to like find a
uh like a email subscript yeah yeah they
have they have updates on the research
down at the bottom I don't know I'm not
a huge I'm not a huge like newsletter
guy I only only read like two
newsletters um but I think this is one
of the ones where I would like create a
filter for it and have it like
automatically starred in my in my uh
Gmail or whatever so I think yeah maybe
we should do that I'm going to I'm going
to add that right now
actually boom there we go can't believe
I wasn't subscribed to that before I
guess you know we see it so quickly
though and we often get the inside scoop
even before it happens because of the
the group chats and stuff so yeah um
yeah I think there's there's lots to be
to be gotten there yeah for sure um all
right dude I got a couple things that I
want to talk about with regards to
smuggling payloads um through sort of uh
obscure
data types that have um I guess some
caveats in the rfcs but before we get
into that let's talk a little bit about
this um Announcement by mckel from
hacker one about better Bounty
transparency for hackers by showing you
what percentage of vulnerabilities are
paid at what tier what are your thoughts
on
that I have thoughts I know you have
thoughts that's why I just open up the
the room to you
man I think generally this was coming
for a good uh a good place um I
think it needs some tweaking for sure so
I think probably the biggest complaint
that I have with it is that it's not
really representative of the current
picture meaning that when you see these
percentages in these average bounties
I'm almost certain I don't see anywhere
that it's mentioned but I'm almost
certain that this is basically alltime
stats um that's what it appears to be
anyways yeah think the tricky part is
that a lot of programs change bounties a
lot of programs don't have a lot of
reports or a lot of resolved reports and
those two things combined can really
skew these stats pretty badly right so
say you're program you're paying okay
let me just add something really quick
for for those of you that haven't
actually seen this yet um what what
happened hacker one it updated their
their sort of built-in um Bounty table
that's a part of the platform built into
the policy page um to reflect how much
uh how many uh how much the average
amount of bounty paid for a specific
type of vulnerability so if you got a
medium and the medium range is like you
know a th000 to 3,000 they'll say okay
the average medium paid is a th000 so
why are they never paying that 3,000
essentially right um you've got that and
then you've also got what percentage of
vulnerabilities lie in what severity in
this program so it does help because you
can look at a specific program and be
like okay well this specific program is
inclined to pay highs in crits um yeah
but like you said that data might be a
little bit
skewed yeah so I I think I would like a
little bit of clarity on some of the
things like percent of sub submissions
for example when it says like 2% of
submissions are criticals does that mean
post triage in general or like on
submission like what what what counts as
a critical when it's paid out like I
don't know um so that that's just one
one thing but I think going back to what
I was what I was speaking on originally
my biggest complaint here is that it
doesn't really account for changes
within the program right so let's say as
an example a program is paying very low
crits let's say they're 1,00 um for for
critical and then they decide to uh
double their bounties triple their
bounties they're not paying 5K crits um
if they never pay a critical their
average Bounty for critical is never
it's never going to reflect that range
right like if let's say between when
they updated it to now they've never
paid a critical bug theyve never
received one they never paid went out so
there's nothing to represent that they
do pay 3K criticals in reality it's just
that the average Bounty that they paid
for a critical is somewhere between Z
and
1500 because that's what they used to
pay for criticals so I think that's it's
not super representative of that I would
like to see it be maybe like since the
last time the Bounty table was updated
or something like that um that could be
gamified from the program side to that
then if they're if they're getting some
stats they they'll be like all right you
know it's not 5K for uh a high it's five
5K to 10K you know like like just making
it clear but also resetting your Bounty
stats um yeah yeah so it is interesting
I have to say um I I love the concept
shout out to hacker one for that in
general I think this sort of
transparency is really helpful and I
think it it solves one problem that
hackers like I mentioned before it
solves one thing that hackers would
really want to look for which is
programs that routinely pay high in
crits right and and it's not necessarily
that you know they their um severity
assessment is off or whatever you know
but it's like that there are highs and
crits to be found and those highs and
crits are getting you know paid out is
the biggest indicator that there are
highs and crits on that program um and I
know a specific hacker um who told me
that this program that he hacks on it's
just everything is a high in a crit you
know and he he has a specific way of of
showing X you know data leakage and it
just always ends up being a higher crit
um and so I bet if we looked at program
side they're super annoyed about that by
the way yeah I maybe maybe you know or
maybe they're happy about it you know
and on one hand you're getting value on
the other hand you this we're not going
to start this again okay you're not ever
gonna no we're not going to go down the
whole like program should play less
bonies to the hackers no no no
um but yeah I think also from a data
perspective this is really interesting
like you were doing a scraping um
project you know a while back that that
sort of um correlated a bunch of data
points and this is another set of data
points you can use for that yeah yeah
absolutely yeah I'm curious if that was
spun off from that or anything you know
I like to think that maybe we had a we
had a piece of that um but yeah it is
pretty interesting to see um you know
this data being more visible
uh you know from the hacker one side so
you know I'm always in favor of program
uh program improvements from the hacker
one side more than hacker improvements
yeah yeah absolutely yeah it's
definitely cool I do I do think that
that um caveat that you mentioned does
need to be addressed though like whe
what is this representing if we slide
our Bounty table you know does
everything paid in a certain range get
reallocated so all if if our crits go
from 2K to 10K and our mediums go to 2K
is they're like all of our bugs are in
the medium bucket now like that that is
interesting yeah yeah yeah um and then
yeah but it's a step in the right
direction so I I think they'll get there
and the hacker one folks I'm sure are
thinking about some of these edge cases
as well so I imagine it's engineered um
close to correct but I am seeing a
couple scenarios where it's like uh they
don't have an average bounty in some and
like the the numbers are a little bit
off uh so I don't know I guess we'll
we'll see what they do with it over the
long term yeah yeah it seems like
they're rolling it out slowly um so I
think it's only on the hacker one
program in a couple others right now but
uh eventually no actually they pushed it
out they pushed it out to everything
okay yeah all right so in the time oh
it's been about a month since this was 3
w we were really behind on news yeah
dude that's the that's the thing like
I'm really glad that you were feeling up
to recording today even though you just
got off a long flight because um we have
had the stuff sitting in the dock for a
while and we need to get it out there so
um yeah thanks for hanging in there dude
um the next two so like I said before
the next two things that I kind of
wanted to talk about are sort of
together but not really um one is a
piece of IPv6 related research uh by
sler um which is essentially how to
smuggle data into ib6 uh IP addresses
and then the other one is smuggling
payloads in phone numbers which I found
from a tweet from Zed shano um and both
of these have similar Concepts which is
there are these data types phone numbers
IPv6 addresses IP addresses in general
can I go ahead what was his name sler
no the other one oh zedan oh no okay so
hey let me let me let me uh let hold up
hold up I am an American where's my
where's my passport hold on where's your
passport no no no I'm sorry I'm sorry
I'm sorry but you know out of respect
for their their culture of
mispronouncing the last letter of the
alphabet uh uh that I I figured I would
show some respect so thank you that case
continue um yeah so um thank you thank
you for that now now you could have just
let me slide by as a respectful person
but now now I had to I had to throw the
it almost it almost slipped through I
was like Z what the
hell I don't know like now I think from
like a from like a hearing perspective I
always when I read it I see I I read Z
shano in my head when I'm talking about
it I've heard so many people say Zed
shano out
loud have you not is that not a thing
that you I only I only ever say Zano
that's I'm all right well I'm Different
potato tomato you know whatever it is
man potato tomato exactly yeah yeah
um I'm sorry dude you're H be a late my
brain's all over Dude Joel you're doing
great man you're doing great I
appreciate you um so let let me talk
about this research okay just shut up
and let me talk about the research real
quick um so the research shows that and
I like the bigger principle associated
with this too which is we have these
data types that we see you know on a
regular basis these
IPv6 um uh IPv6 IP addresses I almost
said domains but we'll get to that um
IPv6 uh IP addresses and uh phone
numbers and we think we know about these
these uh what these data types are
supposed to contain and how they're
supposed to be represented but there's
often caveats to these that live in the
rfcs so I really appreciate the people
that have um taken the Deep dive and
uncovered some of these caveats um so
the the the tldr of This research on
IPv6 um which we'll link down in the
description as well is that there is a
Zone delegation that you can uh a Zone
ID and a Zone delegation that you can um
include in an IPv6 address which is um
delimited by the percent sign or
sometimes percent 25 you know if it's
dou encoded in in the uh or URL encoded
in the scenario um and what this allows
you to do is just kind of add arbitrary
strings after an IPv6 address so it goes
open square bracket colon colon one and
then your percent sign um and then the
zone that you are associating with this
specific this Zone identifier um so what
you can do then is you can say Okay
square bracket colon 1%
25. example.com or something like that
right and when some of these uh host
name parsing
tools are are looking at this they will
consider this IPv6 address to be a part
of that domain so in the in the um in
the write up he described some caveats
in goang and python I think he mentioned
some stuff in C sharp um the browser
does not have any sort of
misconfigurations with regards to this
which is cool um and doesn't really even
support the syntax uh but some of the
parsing that happens for serers side
requests right like you're if you're
doing like a ssrf um will allow you to
include data uh like this so you may be
able to bypass some origin checks on the
server side for those um the other one
from our boy Z or Z Sho uh is is a
similar type of thing um and it also
makes me think of the email the the the
double quotes and the Plus in the email
um but it's a similar thing but for
phone numbers you can add a semicolon
extension equals or phone- context
equals at the end of a phone number and
that is supposed to by the RFC that has
to be accepted as a valid phone number
so if you're using any library to like
parse a phone number and then you like
echoing it straight into the you know
the the HTML response then that's a
great way for you to include xss related
characters there um and and break out of
the context so yeah so one of the
interesting things that zuan called out
here is that
um you know he sort of asked a
rhetorical question of why aren't these
things sanitized and it it's really just
comes down to that a lot of developers
go oh I need to validate an email let me
get the email validation rejects from
sack overflow copy paste is done and it
matches the RFC the problem is
that using an RFC blindly I think is
kind of a mistake right because or even
libr do this right like you should be
using it within the context of how you
need it right like you need a phone
number that means you need a certain
number of digits they don't it doesn't
need to follow the RFC spec needs to be
digits right like uh you know it's not
that complicated but I think it it it
tends to get to a point where things get
a little bit over complicated or you try
to have so much of like a a like a
catchall or like a uh you know adherence
to the RFC where you use some reject
it's like you know you shoot yourself in
the foot ridiculously long right and and
at the end of the day you should have
just looked for like word up to an at
symbol at and then everything not a
space after the at symbol right like so
what you're what you're talking about
Joel is is is
kiss yeah keep keeping it simple keeping
it simple because if as things get more
and more complicated as you start using
libraries to parse phone numbers or
email addresses and and stuff like that
things um yeah there's lots of edge
cases that aren't yeah and and you know
to to give the developers a break here
it you can't just go read the RFC for
every single like thing that you're
you're dealing with and and so it's kind
of um it's kind of just a a function of
the complexity of modern-day
applications and the rfcs that are you
know the building blocks for all all of
this but uh I think for us as hackers it
presents a great opportunity to dive a
little bit deeper and see where we can
smuggle specific data types into tra you
know traditionally trusted data types
like an email address like a phone
number like an ipv
IPv6 address so yeah well right and like
if you think about like the phone number
thing for example like why is a
developer why does every developer who
works with phone numbers need to know
that this is a valid part of the RFC
they don't because most of the time
they're not even using it I'm sure it
was added to the RFC for some random you
know there's some reason for it right um
so you you're sort of left with these
options of okay as a developer do I go
read the RFC find out this Edge case
code around it because I don't need it
but I also want to comply with the RFC
or do you use this Library blindly
because you know that the library
complies with RFC and then you have
these edge cases that you didn't even
know about or do you just write your own
solution that just works for your use
case and probably doesn't comply with
RFC but works really good for however
your using it yeah and and at the end of
the day it's only going to add a little
bit more friction to the end user to be
like okay I got to like rewrite my phone
number with the area code in like dashes
versus like parentheses or whatever um
so yeah complexity there gets tricky and
um but you know that's where we live
that's where we live we live in the
details man so it's a good thing for the
hackers hey guys we're doing something
new this week we decided to launch a
share a bug program through the critical
thinker sub tier on Discord which gives
members of the community an opportunity
to share a bug or attack factor that
they really like and get featured on the
show so this first submission is coming
from mon a hacker that we've talked
about on the podcast before and he's
sharing something specifically regarding
role-based access controls so let's go
ahead and listen to that now there is an
interesting business logic vulnerability
that can occur in SAS platform sometimes
but it has two preconditions the first
precondition is that when new users are
invited to the platform that they're
assigned the default role and this
should be something built into the
platform this shouldn't be like in the
settings this should be part of the
product the second precondition is that
When an Admin invites the user in this
way that they shouldn't be able to
modify that user's permissions while
they're in a pending State and this is
often the case because usually these
users aren't like full users until after
they've accepted the invitation so
usually admins can't modify these
permissions in that
state and this creates a privilege
escalation scenario because let's take
Bob and Alice for example and Bob is an
admin and Alice is intended on having
the lowest possible role but let's say
the default role that they get invited
at is like midlevel well you've got a
situation now where if Alice accepts the
invitation while Bob is asleep well
Alice has more permissions than she
should and this means that she can now
alter resources that she shouldn't be
allowed to and I found this in the past
where the default role was super admin
which is crazy and so when Bob invited
Alice Alice had super admin and was is
able to like de admin Bob and take over
the entire tenant so this isn't super
common but if you keep your eyes peeled
for it like you will find it awesome
great work there mon that is a cool bug
and I've also it actually reminds me of
another piece of research that I saw
which I think was a part of um James
kettle's stuff regarding uh sub States
in in a single HTP request which is
sometimes when a user gets added to an
organization for a split second they
have an admin role um so even if it does
default them to a less privileged role
you can still have uh a very little
little time frame a couple like a
millisecond or so time frame with an
admin um but if it's like mon says in
this specific case then you may just be
able to join the organization remove the
previous owner and take it over so great
attack Vector thank you for sharing
Wonka all right back to the pod
um all right Joel We got a couple places
we can go here I want to spend more time
on the GitHub Enterprise send bug and
the D purify bypass so I'm just going to
mention this bug really quickly that I
saw um Mr Tux racer is definitely a
follow on Twitter that you should be um
you should be following if you're not
already and essentially he doesn't he
doesn't tweet super often despite being
a super badass hacker um and but he did
drop the PC the full PC for C TV 2024
27956 which is an unauthenticated
arbitrary SQL injection in one of the
most popular WordPress plugins automatic
WP automatic um and that's pretty nasty
uh and and so I I've already you know
we're getting to this a little bit late
you know I think he tweeted this end of
April um so it's probably not too much
out there anymore plus WordPress has a
decent auto updating system so uh
hopefully everyone's using that but I
love how this PC was literally just they
took the Q parameter and just stuck it
directly into a like a like an SQL call
like you you literally just write the
whatever SQL uh that you want in this Q
parameter and that's it uh and so he he
dropped a PCC to just essentially add a
new a new user to the wp admin and get
RC from that um so classic classic move
there and these WordPress bugs we got to
keep an eye on them man because
WordPress is all over the
place yeah man I mean I love Mr Tu like
Mr Tux racer is one of those you know
you said he doesn't really tweet much uh
I like to think of myself as one of
those people mostly just because I don't
use Twitter yeah it's not because I'm
stoic or anything it's just because
uh I don't I I don't say
anything it's not CU I don't have things
to say uh it's just that yeah totally
it's not yeah well you know we we
essentially you're tweeting you know for
an hour every week with me on the Pod so
it's just coming out out on the maybe
I'll start tweeting a transcript of
everything I say oh jeez you get like a
chat gbt bot to go through and parse it
and then just shoot it on
twitter Justin shut up I'm trying to
explain something that's the only tweet
that goes out so good man um these next
two ones are interesting super
interesting um the GitHub Enterprise
send bug and the D purify bypass and
I've actually got a little something to
add to the Dom purify bypass i h uh that
is not mass mass consumed I don't have
the PC but I do have a little bit more
information um so where do you want to
go you want to do the GitHub Enterprise
bug first or the D purify stuff where
wherever your heart desires all right my
heart's my heart's feeling D purify um
so uh I haven't seen the PC out if it's
out yet um I did spend some time looking
at it because I expected it it to be
pretty simple to reproduce because of
how the patch looked but uh I think it's
using a lot of different different stuff
um and I did have a conversation with
with Yota uh about this um that's otak
on on Twitter and on Discord and um he
definitely has done a little bit more
research into it and has a semi viable
PC that he shared with me uh but it only
affects a certain um segment uh of the
of the market market so it's not it's
not super relevant um but I also did
listen to a podcast in Japanese about
this uh because and and I'll shout them
out it's the uh uh let me see I think I
want to get the name right I think it's
j JP bug Bounty podcast um let me see if
I can find it Well I'll link it down in
the description it's bug Bounty JP
podcast um okay and it's a podcast
that's put on by uh moo which is my it's
fully in Japanese it's fully in Japanese
so uh for those of you that speak
Japanese
great and I think the the content of
that was a little bit tricky for me to
get my Japanese
is me and especially when he says as he
just spits some crazy Japanese like my
Japanese is is I can speak all right but
the listening to native speakers talk
about highlevel hacking Concepts is a
little bit tricky
um but they did talk on that podcast a
little bit about um rota's experience
trying to reverse some of this stuff and
obviously if you look at the um the
patch there's um something to do with
with depth of nodes um with regards to
this da purify bypass so there's there's
definitely you're going to need to you
know stack uh various amounts of um divs
and and tags together um and then the
piece that I sort of got out of that
which which I hadn't seen before was
then it it also results in a a namespace
confusion so at some point Dom purify is
thinking that it's parsing you know SVG
Nam space or or mathml Nam space um and
it's actually parsing HTML or vice versa
um and the the Overflow of that you know
nesting that's the word I was looking
for nesting of those elements and then
also that sort of namespace confusion
together leads to um some variants of
the D purify bypasses that have been
affecting um that Library recently so
that's all I've got I wish I could get I
wish I could give more but you know yot
is also I trolled him a little bit on
Twitter about this too he's he's very um
he's very sensitive about disclosing
information that he could be even
remotely related to a vulnerability that
he doesn't have permission to speak
about so um even like even that was so
my my menty was like you know he's like
pulling teeth to get it out of them so
we work with what we can
get yeah so I will say when it first
came out I I I did take a look at the uh
the patch myself as well and uh it's not
very difficult to figure out how it
works um you know if you're if you're
curious uh go look there's a single uh
commit that has everything you need to
know in it yeah but okay let me say let
me say though Joel I also thought the
same thing but you can't get the PC out
of that like you can get the concepts
but it is not very easy to get the PC
out of that yeah but it gives you a
really good starting point it does it
does um so that one's that um all right
two two things and then we can wrap it
and you can get some sleep Joel um the
GitHub Enterprise bug dude what a
masterpiece uh so cool did you get the
chance to read through that whole thing
yeah man uh so I think I actually put
this in the in the doc last last week um
and was so in depth that I was trying to
figure out how to even like summarize it
um it's just one of those super
technical really interesting bugs that
has a lot of context and a lot of like
code in it you know what I mean so um if
you're like a ruby nerd or you like
auditing gitlab or GitHub or hacker one
which I think are the only three
services left on the internet using Ruby
no no everything uses Ruby
man no no no everything uses nextjs now
come okay that's true you're not wrong
about that um yeah no absolutely I
totally agree very well done write up um
technically
in-depth intriguing uh long but worth
the read for sure and not only that it
took geez uh six months between when it
was disclosed and when it got uh
published oh really oh wow yeah I think
so yeah so they disclosed this initially
like end of December man can you imagine
POV it's December
26th dude that's so bad he drops 26th
that you just get an RC reported to your
bug b yeah literally in the backstory
section back in early December 2023 I
was performing some research on
ghes wait oh on the day I went on
vacation I located a potentially minor
bug fast forward to the day after
Christmas you're right dude December 26
what the freak oh my gosh it's brutal
dude did we learn nothing from the whole
Tanner Pete yorski situation like we
talked about that on the on the Pod
before right Tanner dropped a uh Cash
Money dropped a mega crit on Pete on
like Christmas day one time and Pete had
to like leave his family on Christmas
day to go deal with this like really bad
bug um
so security
stop for no sleep okay seriously man
seriously no no man um yeah very cool
one I did have a couple takeaways from
this one one just read it because we're
not going to talk about it it's too
technical uh to actually try to talk
through on the Pod um but there is a
takeaway from this which I tweeted about
and uh it didn't the Tweet didn't do as
well as I hoped it would for the sole
purpose of people understanding how how
this works so I'm going to I'm going to
sort of reiterate a little bit of what I
talked about on the tweet in the Tweet
here on the Pod um it I outlined a
couple ways or a couple things you
should pay extra attention to when doing
source code review and one of them was
uh indirect method invocation and I I
sort of nested it down a little bit
further on purpose for the people that
dig a little bit deeper and are going to
just not read the the you know between
the first fold of my tweet and kind of
like click in a little bit so for those
of you that that spend the time reading
my tweets thank you
um but I also want to reward our
listeners here so um I I did want to
call out this is something that I've
seen this is a trend that I've seen um
where vulnerabilities occur due to this
whole indirect method invocation thing
and there are lots of ways to do this in
in different languages in Ruby uh as we
saw in this write up it's it's object.
send in PHP you can actually just call a
string and it will and it will execute
that function in Python you can access
globals um uh you can do a call to
globals and then provide a a string name
and then call that string and it will um
and it will run that um in Java there's
lots of ways to do it in JS there's lots
of ways to do it um so this whole
concept of taking input from the user
and allowing some function to be called
whether it be on an object or whether it
just be you know sort of evow and you
can just kind of you know run an OS
system or whatever um and run a command
uh it's not normally that simple and so
looking looking for scenarios where it's
limited but you can call things on
various objects or like parent classes
and that sort of thing is really
powerful and has resulted in a lot of
bugs yeah I will say um one interesting
thing I've noticed when I look for stuff
like this and typically if I find
something like this I'll go and I'll
look for other instances of it and it
almost never exists I don't know if you
find this too but like oh really
it's so weird like if I find something
super complex and like crazy like this
I'll G be like oh maybe they're doing
the same mistake elsewhere and it's like
I've literally stumbl on like the only
instance in the entire code base where
this happens yeah yeah it happens man I
mean uh we ran into a couple things like
that in a live hacking event a while
back but I will say the time that you
and I went Ham on uh on some source code
review at a live hacking event last year
there were multiple instances of of
things so I I think it depends on the
situation I think it depends on the
situation um but definitely I'm gonna
just read out some of these really
quickly um templating is like really big
when it comes to getting RC on a service
when you're actually looking at the
source code if you can figure out a way
to get your input as uh to be
interpreted as templates that's massive
and of course um uh you know any sort of
interaction with files any sort of
interactions with external Services
whether it be apis whether it be like a
redus you know something like that all
of those are are really big um
deserialization of binary formats of
yaml of Json all of these things can
result in unintended stuff um whether
you know sometimes you can get prototype
pollution sometimes you can um just get
straight rce if it's it's uh um
arbitrary deserialization um so I think
sometimes I get just speaking from
personal experience when I I look at
these massive applications and I finally
have access to the source code I'm like
all right let's go like let's let's get
it and then I open it up in vs code and
vs code takes like an hour opens up cuz
it's so freaking massive and then I'm
just like a little bit intimidated I'm
like how am I ever going to find this um
but having a sort of a list of all right
let me look at this this this and this
and work back from the sinks and I know
Joel I know that you're gonna give me
that stupid face that you're giving me
right now because of of of what I've of
what I've said in the past about about
sources and syns um and light preferring
sources I think that but you gotta go
has their own some people listen
everybody's a little bit different some
people go syns some people go
sources um I think there's arguments to
be made for either one yeah and and I
think there are and I think for me it's
largely a function of app size if your
app is not that huge um I think it makes
sense to go after sources and I think
going after sources is a really good
investment of time for you in a lot of
ways because you can understand the app
how it's architected much better but at
the end of the day if you're trying to
take that and you're trying to turn if
you have a very specific goal I want
unauthenticated RC on this I want you
know SQL injection whatever it be you
got to work you got to work backwards
from the syns um and then because if you
don't that a lot of times these apps are
too big and you you're just GNA burn too
much time yeah like trying to find
potential you know entry points is like
anything can be an entry point right
like I I agree with that right like I
think depending on this the size of the
app like certain things you might end up
falling down rabbit holes where you're
like oo there's an eval call here and
then it's like you you spend 4 hours
looking at every single eval call and
turns out it's like a systemic way that
they've safely done it yeah that's fine
like I think that's also a good use of
time I see you speaking from experience
here Joel you're talking about a random
example I pulled out of my
head dude I love how you just like
straight up read our our chat from that
event man they're like there's eval
everywhere this is going to be a shell
and then you know8 hour later we're like
not a single freaking use of you now is
actually so funny dude screw that man
that yeah well at least we sheld it man
so that that that helps um all right
cool so I've said my piece on that um
Last Thing Before I Let You Go Joel is I
wanted to give a shout out to my boy
riddle um riddle has been doing some
awesome Dev on kaido and I I just was in
the K of chat and I was like oh man
wouldn't it be cool if there was a
button in
Replay that would go through your HTP
request history grab the latest request
and extract certain amount of headers
and update your cookies for you so you
so like when your session dies you don't
have to go back to your HTP history and
like grab the the latest uh you know
cross- site request forgery header or
like grab the latest cookie and like
paste it in and update your session and
if you're like working over multiple
sessions or whatever and you've got like
all these named tag it's all organized
but all the sessions are dead so it
doesn't work anymore it's just it's a
pain and so I I put that in the chat and
then I like looked back a couple hours
later and Riddle's like I got it and and
he he had pushed it he had built it it
works awesome and he's actually got it
pushed to the ever um your even better
extensions um sort of manager as well
for kaido so essentially you install
even better extensions and you just
click the install button on refreshes
replay headers and now there's a button
right next to the send button um in your
in your replay Tab and you just press
update headers you can specify what
headers you want in a little drop down
menu and it will pull the latest header
from HTTP history update your your
current replay Tab and just get your
session right back on track with one
click um sweet it it's just so clutch
man it it like that sort of thing is it
just Smooths over your whole experience
and shade here it's almost like uh when
you don't have to write your plugins in
jython and
Java it's so much easier to extend the
application yeah yeah I I I don't know
any software that uh is architected like
that yeah that was just a Rand thought I
had just just I mean I'm glad you shared
that you know just out of the out of the
as it bubbles up you know you know and
and to be honest man I as a python
Fanboy I did critique kaido in the
beginning for leaning towards JavaScript
but JavaScript is great dude you know
JavaScript is is in a lot of spots you
know you're not really context switching
you know from between the front end and
the back end so much um it's very
versatile it's it's pretty fast in this
environment so yeah like 95% of hackers
know how to read it and you and like use
it that's that's that's a great Point as
well you know you it it is mandatory for
you to be if you know if you're using an
HTTP proxy you need to know some
JavaScript um so I think it was a great
decision and uh I I think we can see
dividends being paid from it because the
the kaido development Community is
really um thriving right now and there's
a lot of really good uh uh extensions
being added into the into the flow and
uh especially beex and riddle have been
really crushing it lately I'll be really
curious to see if kaido decides to do
any sort of like centralization or
anything with the plugins like like burp
did because um I don't think it's
necessarily like a bad move but it is
kind of interesting to see them sort of
like take over so to speak like the
plugins and whatever yeah we we are
going to do that um just for those of
you that aren't aware I I'm an adviser
for kaido and so I do have a little bit
of insight into that that that will be
um something that happens in the future
uh whether it be something like this
like the the even better extensions
Library um where it's controlled by the
community and then there's like you know
a pull request into a certain GitHub
repo or whatever or whether it's done at
the kaido level um in in a similar
format uh there will be some sort of
centralization of plugins um and and
even now with the with the uh even
better extensions Library uh it makes it
really or Plugin it makes it really easy
to just oneclick install plugins and
that sort of thing so um really really
excited to see that progression yeah
absolutely that's super exciting I I
like having a man on the inside it's uh
yeah dude you know I'll try to P you
know and I I've I've gained a lot of
value from it too as well you know um
it's been cool to see to have to help
guide the vision of how people use the
tool because I use the tool all the time
constantly it's literally open every day
all day in my on my computer um so I
think from the perspective of literally
just using it 247 um I think there's a
lot of value that can be be added from
having that experience so uh it's been
fun it's been fun and we're going to
continue trying to to Really serve the
the power user community and get people
really comfortable in there um and
remove that friction of okay I have to
think about using this tool and more
just you're just focusing on the
hacking yeah yeah absolutely yeah yeah
that and that's been my biggest thing
about kaido is like the less I have to
focus on using the tool and the more I
can just use the tool the better well
and there's going to be friction man
that it's the problem is is I've even
talked to them a little bit about like
wouldn't it be cool if there was some
sort of like not like burp compatibility
mode or something like that like
something that makes that transition a
little bit easier because when you're
moving from burp to kaido for the first
week it sucks I'm not even going to lie
and there are a lot of great features
like that you're like oh I really like
this um but you're G to have to think
about how to use the tool for the first
week but then once you get in there and
you start using the tool and you start
understanding the power of workflows and
and these extensions that are in place
and and the distributed architecture and
you're just popping back and forth from
your couch to your desktop you know with
ease without having to move your files
anything like that um there's a lot of
added value to that for me uh but you
got to get over that hump in the
beginning so yeah it's tricky yeah
absolutely all right man you got
anything else you want to add about I
mean I guess you haven't really really
done anything at Bounty con yet you just
got off the plane so we'll Deb from that
next week yeah yeah yeah we'll see we'll
see all right man sounds good get some
rest have fun thank you all right peace
peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb show/
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack alongs exclusive
scripts and an exclusive chat Channel
with us we'll see you there